Fausto Lopez

Data & Analytics Manager

Personal Info

Address

110-23 55th Ave 2nd floor Corona New York 11368

Phone

646-639-3360

E-mail

FaustoLopez110@gmail.com

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/lopezfausto

www

www.faustolopez.com

Hard Skills

Automation

Advanced

Data Visualization

Advanced

Database Knowledge

Good

Languages

R

Advanced

SQL

Advanced

Python

Good

Javascript

Beginner

Soft Skills

Resourcefulness

Expert

Leadership

Advanced

Creative and resourceful data scientist with 5+ years experience munging, wrangling and analyzing data. Expanded big data analytical processes at the NYC Taxi and Limousine Commission by 50% and increased access to new Key Performance Indicators for a rapidly evolving industry. Developed big data pipelines and migration strategies, built comprehensive dashboards along with multiple databases and increased query and reporting speeds by over 500%. Developed and lead a team of 4 analysts working on over 300 gigabytes of data.

Experience

2016-07 -

present

Data & Analytics Manager

Taxi & Limousine Commission of New York

- Design and automate analytical frameworks to produce internal and public facing metrics on over 1 billion taxi trip records, creating Shiny/Tableau dashboards and tracking KPIs.
- Designed and built Postgres and Clickhouse databases hosting Citi Bike, taxi and driver income data and increasing reporting speeds by over 500%.
- Rapid prototype dashboard tools, analytical processes, ETL procedures and customer applications in partnership with data engineers and IT personnel for production release.
- Spearheaded landmark Driver Income study leading to first national vehicle cap on ride sharing companies and minimum driver pay.
- Launched Analytics Blog meant to showcase innovative and interesting insights and visualizations on all things taxi related.
- Applied regression and random forest models to predict taxi volume and k-means clustering to improve 311 complaint categories for taxis.

2015-06 -

Data & Evaluation Manager

2016-06 Urban Upbound

- Oversaw and managed over 6 separate databases to track outcomes and reporting.
- Developed evaluation protocols and analytical tools for testing program models.
- Assisted in designing and implementing a study on financial stress as a predictor of financial counseling outcomes.
- In partnership with New York Women's Foundation, designed and implemented the Healthy Aging Study, a qualitative report recommending resource upgrades for senior citizens in Far Rockaway.

2014-07 -

Monitoring & Evaluation Assistant

2015-05

Urban Upbound

- Designed and implemented analytical tools.
- Developed evaluation protocols for testing program models.
- Analyzed data and produced quality reports.
- Assisted in survey construction.

Education

2009-08 -

Macaulay Honors College at CUNY – Hunter College

2014-05

Masters of Science in Applied Social Research

Bachelor of Arts in Sociology

Publications

2018-06 An Earnings Standard for New York City's App-Based Drivers: Economic Analysis and

Policy Assessment

2015-06 Hybrid Strategies: Allocating Involvement in the Digital Age, In Society for the Study of

Symbolic Interaction